All right, congratulations.
حسنًا، تهانينا.
You've successfully wrangled a data set.
لقد قمت بمعالجة مجموعة البيانات بنجاح.
You've completed the entire wrangling process from gathering, to assessing,
لقد أكملت عملية المعالجة بالكامل من التجميع، إلى التقييم
and through cleaning your data, which meant defining,
مرورًا بمسح بياناتك، وهو ما يعني تحديد
coding, and testing cleaning operations.
عمليات المسح وترميزها واختبارها.
After we are happy with the state of our data,
وبعد أن نكون راضين بحالة بياناتنا،
and we are for the purpose of this walkthrough,
ونقوم بذلك هنا بغرض المعاينة،
now it's time to act on it.
حان الآن وقت العمل على ذلك.
Which can mean analysis and visualization,
وهو ما يمكن أن يعني التحليل والمرئيات.
which we'll do right now.
وهو ما سنقوم به الآن.
What insights do we want to pull out of this data?
ما الرؤى التي نرغب في استخراجها من هذه البيانات؟
It's about job postings,
إنها عن طلبات الوظائف،
so maybe one thing that would be useful to know would be the percentage of postings
لذا، ربما يكون من المفيد معرفة نسبة الطلبات
that are looking for someone to start urgently, that is ASAP.
التي تبحث عن شخصٍ ما لاستلام الوظيفة بشكل عاجل، أي في أسرع وقت ممكن.
That's one good angle for analysis and we now have
هذه زاوية جيدة للتحليل، لدينا الآن بيانات
nicely clean data for that as well in our start date column.
ممسوحة بشكل جيد لهذا الغرض، وكذلك في عمود تاريخ البدء لدينا.
Because the focus of this course is data wrangling and not data analysis,
ونظرًا لأن هذه الدورة التدريبية تركّز على تعارض البيانات وليس تحليل البيانات،
I'm just going to show you how the code works for this analysis here.
سأوضح لكم كيفية عمل الكود في هذا التحليل هنا.
But there'll be a Jupyter Notebook below
ولكن سيكون هناك Jupyter Notebook أسفل هذا الفيديو
this video for you to do it yourself if you'd like to.
لتتمكن من القيام بذلك بنفسك إذا كنت ترغب في ذلك.
I encourage you to explore.
وأنا أشجعك على استكشاف ذلك بنفسك.
When doing simple calculations like these,
عند إجراء عمليات حسابية بسيطة كهذه،
I like to physically write down the numerator and denominator.
أحب كتابة البسط والمقام.
It helps me to isolate the problem.
حيث يساعدني ذلك في عزل المشكلة.
A percentage or fraction has a numerator and denominator.
نسبة مئوية أو كسور تحتوي على بسط ومقام.
Again, we're looking for percentage of postings that
ومن جديد، نحن نبحث عن النسبة المئوية لطلبات الوظائف
are looking for someone to start urgently,
التي تبحث عن شخصٍ ما لاستلام الوظيفة بشكل عاجل،
that is ASAP. There we go.
أي في أسرع وقت ممكن. هيا نواصل.
Number of ASAP start dates divided by number of non-empty start dates.
عدد الطلبات ذات تواريخ البدء العاجلة مقسومًا على تواريخ البدء غير الفارغة.
All right, so here's how the code works.
حسنًا، إليك كيفية عمل الكود.
We can use value_counts function again and pick out this ASAP count,
يمكننا استخدام دالة value_counts مرة أخرى واختيار عدد التواريخ العاجلة هذا،
6,856, which we should see here, and boom, great.
وهو 6،856، والذي يجب أن نراه هنا، وها هو قد ظهر، رائع.
That's our numerator.
هذا هو البسط خاصتنا.
And for the non-empty counts,
وبالنسبة إلى الأعداد غير الفارغة،
we can just use the count function.
يمكننا فقط استخدام دالة العدّ.
This excludes all of the NaN entries, 9,675.
ويستثني هذا جميع مدخلات NaN، 9,675.
That should be the same value we see in our info function, and yes.
ويجب أن تكون نفس القيمة التي نراها في دالة المعلومات، ونعم.
StartDate, 9,675, non-null objects.
StartDate، 9,675، الأشياء غير الفارغة.
Non-null meaning non-empty or non-NaN.
غير خالي بمعنى غير فارغ أو non-NaN.
And all we have to do now is divide the two, numerator by denominator,
وكل ما علينا القيام به الآن هو قسمة الاثنين، البسط على المقام،
and okay, approximately 71% of job postings have an urgent start date.
أحسنتم، تقريبًا 71 من طلبات الوظائف التي تتضمن تواريخ بدء عاجلة.
Wow, okay, that's way higher than I would have guessed.
يا إلهي، أحسنتم، هذا أفضل بكثير مما توقعت.
It would be awesome if we could make a chart showing
سيكون رائعًا إذا تمكننا من إعداد مخطط يوضح
the distribution of start dates in the data.
توزيع تواريخ البدء في البيانات.
That's where visualization comes in.
وفي هذه المرحلة، يأتي دور المرئيات.
Let's convert this analysis to a vis.
دعونا نحوّل هذا التحليل إلى vis.
We'll create a pie chart and yes,
سنقوم بإنشاء مخطط دائري،
pie charts are okay sometimes.
والمخططات الدائرية تعمل بشكل جيد أحيانًا.
Again, I'll walk you through the code here since
ومرة أخرى، سأنقلكم إلى الكود هنا
this course isn't about data visualization.
لأن هذه الدورة التدريبية لا تتعلق بمؤثرات عرض البيانات.
There again will be opportunity to code
وهنا أيضًا، ستكون هناك فرصة للترميز
along in the Jupyter Notebook below this video though, if you want to.
في Jupyter Notebook أسفل هذا الفيديو، إذا كنت ترغب في ذلك.
Okay, so here's our visualization code.
حسنًا، ها هو كود المرئيات.
Again, using our value_counts function and we attach this plot function.
سنقوم بإرفاق دالة الرسم باستخدام دالة value_counts الخاصة بنا.
We want a pie chart and press shift enter,
نريد مخططًا دائريًا ونضغط على shift enter،
and that should be it. Actually, I lied.
وهذا ما يجب أن تكون عليه. في الواقع، لقد كذبت.
We need to put this little bit of code here first to
نحتاج إلى وضع هذا الجزء البسيط من الكود هنا أولًا
display the plots within our notebook,
لعرض الرسومات في دفتر الملاحظات الخاص بنا،
and there is our pie chart.
كما يوجد مخططنا الدائري.
It's pretty ugly though because there are so many labels here addressing
إنه أمر سيء للغاية رغم وجود العديد من التسميات هنا
every single entry in the value counts output which you can see up here.
التي تتناول جميع المدخلات في نتائج أعداد القيم التي تراها هنا.
There's so many. So, we'll import a library called numpy,
هذا كثير جدًا. لذلك، سنقوم باستيراد مكتبة تسمى numpy،
short form or alias, np.
أو نموذج قصير أو اسم مستعار، np.
Then we'll create a custom array of
وبعد ذلك سنقوم بإنشاء مصفوفة مخصصة من
labels and this array will have the same length as our value_counts output.
التسميات، وسيكون لهذه المصفوفة نفس طول ناتج value_counts.
The array will start off empty or i.e.
ستبدأ المصفوفة كمصفوفة فارغة أو أي
this empty string here with type object.
سلسلة فارغة هنا مع كائن النوع.
This gets into the nitty gritty details of
ويحدث هذا في التفاصيل المهمة لـ
numpy so don't stress if this doesn't make sense to you currently.
numpy، لذا لا تتوتر إذا كان هذا غير منطقي بالنسبة لك حاليًا.
And let's make the first label in that array,
ودعونا ننشأ التسمية الأولى في تلك المصفوفة،
ASAP, because the first entry is ASAP here.
ASAP، لأن السطر الأول هنا هو ASAP.
And check out that vis.
تحقق من vis هذا.
That's a lot of urgent postings, 71% approximately.
هذا كثير من طلبات الوظائف العاجلة، 71٪ تقريبًا.